(I'm Back)
Gosh, I haven't driven on this road in a while.
(She drives past a serene, green field...)
(and quietly heads somewhere.)
(Na Rae leans on her car and wipes away her tears.)
(Soon after, she starts walking with heaviness in her steps.)
(She crouches down after barely taking a few steps.)
(She musters up her courage and stands in front of the gate.)
This is so hard. What am I going to do?
Grandma, Grandpa. I'm here.
Oh, no.
(With no friendly greetings returned,)
(the house is filled with only silence.)
(It's the house of her grandparents...)
- Grandma! - My gosh.
(she loved with all of her heart.)
Come on in.
- Grandma! - Hey.
(Her family used to give her a warm welcome from the gate.)
Did you drive here?
Yes.
All right.
(She made unforgettable memories with her grandparents at the house.)
I like it. It's beautiful.
I'm so proud of you, Na Rae.
(Grandma, Grandpa. I'm here.)
How am I going to do this?
(She's unable to move at the unfamiliar sight.)
Their house was always clean.
I just couldn't believe my eyes when I saw how messy it was.
I don't think I could've gone inside.
It was your 1st time seeing the house after 2 years, right?
- Yes. - Right.
- I only saw it from a distance. - I see.
- Going in must've terrified you. - Right.
(She braces herself and enters the house.)
Everything looks the same.
(The pictures are hanging in the same spots as before.)
Oh, no.
The pictures are still hanging here.
The massage chair I bought for them is still here.
After my grandparents passed away...
You know, there's a healthy period for grieving.
But I couldn't give myself time to grieve.
I had this dream every day.
In my dream, my grandma looked so healthy.
When I woke up from it, I believed it to be real.
Then ten minutes later,
I'd realise that she had passed away.
And all of a sudden, I'd cry at night.
I thought I would break down if I went back to their house.
So I've been putting it off.
(So I couldn't come here.)
Actually, six months before my grandpa's passing,
my grandparents moved into a nursing hospital together.
My grandpa passed away all of a sudden.
Then my grandma stayed at the nursing hospital.
Our family took turns to look after them.
No one had the time or energy to fix up the house or do anything.
This house was the last thing on our mind.
Then...
my uncle came to the house and tried to clean it up.
It must've been too much for him to handle alone.
At her funeral, I told my family that I would take care of it.
(I decided to help with the rest of the house.)
Actually,
my family cleaned some parts of the house.
There were a few last items they couldn't sort out.
I told them I would take care of them.
It took a lot of courage on my part...
to visit their house after two years.
I see.
So, I...
I couldn't calm down.
(Overwhelmed by profound sadness, she struggled to calm down.)
They were in my dream every day.
But I just couldn't bring myself to go to their house.
It's not easy.
(Right, it's not easy.)
This requires courage too.
- It was too much for me to handle. - Yes.
Hold on.
(With courage, she studies the traces of her grandparents.)
(Her grandma used to cool the water in case it was too hot...)
(for her grown-up granddaughter.)
(At her grandma's usual spot...)
(Before breakfast, after breakfast, after lunch, after dinner)
(Only a trace of frozen time lingers.)
This is our house.
I was born and lived here until I was nine years old.
And...
this is my grandparents' house.
(The house of my dear grandparents)
- Don't give me a lot of rice. - Why not?
I'm on a diet.
You're all skin and bones.
(The house...)
I hope you don't have to leave.
(where people who cherished and loved me once lived)
(She pulls weeds in the yard with her bare hands.)
Watch your hands.
That was the furthest thing from my mind.
They're completely overgrown.
Gosh, I can't seem to pull this out. This is so annoying.
I noticed later that I had scraped my hands.
Back then, I didn't feel any pain. I just couldn't stand still.
It took too long for me to come back here.
(In no time, there's a pile of weeds in the yard.)
The overgrown weeds...
Seriously. They looked so awful.
I wanted to pull all of them out.
They're all broken.
My grandma used to cherish them.
They must've been outside for too long.
This is the only one that's not broken.
All done.
Park Na Rae.
Na Rae.
Open the gate.
My gosh. Look at you. You've been crying.
- It was a long trip, right? - Why are you crying?
When did you get here?
An hour ago.
(Patting her on the back without saying a word)
I once talked to Kian84 and Hyun Moo about this.
I told them that I wanted to be the one...
to take down their pictures.
I told them that...
I wanted this house to always be clean and cosy...
just like when they were alive.
You were so young. Gosh, look how young you were.
Then they were willing to come and help me.
So I'm so grateful that they came all this way.
It's been eight years...
since you visited her grandma's house, right?
It's been eight years.
- Really? - Yes.
Seeing how she wanted both of us, there must be a lot of work.
They came early in the morning.
I wonder if the wooden bench is still there.
- Do you remember it? - Yes.
Na Rae gave us cold coffee there.
Yes, that's right.
You know what I remember?
We cooked ginseng chicken soup.
It feels like that was 18 years ago, not 8 years.
It's been so long.
They came all this way just because I asked.
This wasn't an easy thing to do. I was so grateful.
As we told you before, we also have a lot of memories...
- about the house. - Right.
- We had a good memory there. - Right.
- We had so much fun. - It felt like...
being on summer vacation from school...
- Right. - as grown-ups.
- We had fun like school kids. - We did.
She recalled our memory from eight years ago...
and asked me to help her. I was grateful for that.
Actually, my paternal grandmother passed away...
when I was 20 years old.
My maternal grandmother passed away before I turned 30.
When I was young,
I was going to follow my grandma once she passed.
- I was like that as a kid. - Same here.
Given my history,
I could understand what she was going through.
When I was about to enter the house, even I thought...
I couldn't walk in. You know what I mean?
This house means...
This kind of emotion must have hit Na Rae harder than it hit me.
I got emotional too.
When she opened the gate, I saw her puffy eyes.
I got emotional too. But I couldn't break down with her.
I thought that would make her break down in tears.
So I pretended to be indifferent about that.
Sit down.
- You made us cold coffee here. - Right, the bench is still here.
It's still here.
- But everything here is... - Yes?
worn down and rusty.
I might have to throw everything out.
I couldn't handle it. I didn't know where to start.
I bet you felt lost.
We'll do whatever you want.
This is...
- I don't know where to start. - Right. This is...
Let's throw out some things.
Why don't we go over there?
- Show us around. - Okay.
- I had to show them inside. - Yes.
I remember spending the night here.
Right.
They cleaned the floor, so it's clean inside.
Let's take off our shoes.
This is...
It still smells the same.
The smell of a house in the countryside.
Yes. I remember the house.
Look. That's us.
(Look at the photo of us.)
- My goodness. - Hey.
- My goodness. - Hey. When was that?
My grandparents really loved you guys.
- My grandparents loved them. - Oh, my.
I didn't know they hung the photo here.
- They were so healthy back then. - Right.
- So I couldn't bring myself... - How sad.
to take down these pictures.
But why do you want to take them down?
First of all, there's a leak in the house.
The wallpapers are so mouldy.
Once one part gets mouldy,
- it will spread all over the house. - It will spread.
So I learned how to put up wallpapers...
and plaster the walls, so I could fix the ceiling.
But I must take them down to fix up the house.
But I just couldn't take...
- the photos down myself. - That's understandable.
- You want to do some repair work. - Yes.
If we leave the house as it is,
- it might be a deserted house. - The house will be ruined.
- The house will be damaged. - Right.
I don't know where to begin.
We have to report the items before throwing them out, right?
I think we passed that point.
- Right. - We need to hire a service for it.
I have so much stuff to throw out in the yard.
I'm glad they went.
- Kian84 is a hard worker. - Right.
Hyun Moo too.
- You included me out of respect. - Yes.
You know what? Having them there was a huge help.
- I mean it. - Right.
You need someone to decide on the order.
Someone who can make sound judgment and prioritise.
- Hyun Moo was great at that. - Yes.
Hyun Moo did things that required thinking.
And I took care of physical tasks.
- That's a nice way of putting it. - Yes.
"Thinking."
(Scanning the house while thinking)
What about the fridge? Will you throw it out?
I'm not sure. But my uncle...
took out all the food in the fridge.
- The fridge still works. - Food...
Is there another fridge here?
That's the primary fridge.
- And this is... - Is it a kimchi fridge?
Gosh, it's kimchi.
Oh, no. Did your grandma make it?
(Kimchi made by her grandparents is still in the fridge.)
(She bursts into tears at the sight of their trace.)
Their kimchi holds...
- a lot of meaning for me. - Right.
- It was still in the fridge. - It was.
I can't control myself right now.
- Both of us... - Come on.
Come on, guys. You could've given her a hug.
- Both of us are INTP. - What was that?
Are you guys there as waste haulers?
- What was that? - Are you there as waste haulers?
You know what? Even hired help would ask me...
- if I was okay. - Right. Even they'd ask her that.
- What are you guys looking at? - Right?
- Nothing was in front of them. - I was looking at the weeds.
Why did you rest your hands on your waist?
- We didn't know what to do. - We didn't know what to do.
I didn't want to say the wrong thing.
- Right. - Right?
- You know what we're like. - Of course.
- I might say the wrong thing there. - Right.
I liked that they said nothing because that's who they are.
- If they tried to comfort me, - Like giving you a hug.
- I would've been puzzled. - It would've been weird.
Everyone has their way of comforting people...
- based on their personality. - Right.
Yes.
This...
(Leaning)
- So this is a common thing. - Yes.
When grandparents pass away, kimchi becomes the reminder.
- Right. - There's always kimchi.
I'm suddenly not sad anymore.
It's iffy to throw that out.
No.
KEY has been keeping...
his grandma's beef bone soup for 13 years.
- I can't eat that. - Right.
- Exactly. - Yes.
Come on.
Think of us as AI that hasn't been upgraded yet.
(The outdated AI that hasn't been upgraded)
They're super behind with the updates.
But you guys probably didn't eat anything yet.
- We should go out to eat... - Yes.
and buy cleaning supplies.
We can hire a service...
- to get rid of big items here. - Okay.
- And... - What about the sofa?
Do you think we can salvage it?
But the thought of throwing it out...
- But that sofa... - Right.
- I can't throw it out. - It's...
My grandparents always sat on that sofa.
- The creases are still there. - Right.
I don't think you can use this.
- Probably not. - No.
- You think so? - It's iffy even to donate this...
- to a community center. - Or...
should I take a picture of this and put it up online to sell?
Should I put it up online to sell?
Why would I do that?
(Should I take a picture of this and put it up online to sell?)
This is so embarrassing.
I shouldn't laugh.
- Are you serious? - Gosh.
My grandparents used to sit on that sofa!
- Listen. - It still had their creases.
You wanted to sell that?
Listen. I thought you were going to throw it out.
I thought it would be more meaningful...
- for the sofa to meet a new owner. - What?
Were you trying to get more points on the app?
- Gosh, he's so funny. - They must be really close.
- You can say that to a best friend. - That's totally possible.
- I'm sorry. I... - He's practically her brother.
- He wanted to be helpful. - Of course.
He wanted to say something helpful.
Should I take a picture of this and put it up online to sell?
Why would I do that?
(My bad.)
Hey.
Do you want to get hit by the phone?
(Come to your senses.)
- My grandparents used to sit on it. - Okay.
How could I sell it online?
I didn't know.
My gosh.
I was quite shocked. I couldn't believe what you said.
(I'm sorry about him.)
(Sobbing)
(In a tight spot)
Let me use the bathroom.
(Then he runs away.)
My gosh.
What kind of person would say that?
He was just trying to help in any way he could.
He meant well.
Get lost to the bathroom.
(Unable to fix the situation)
Get in there.
Here's what's important. How do you plan on using the house?
I'll remove the wallpapers...
(Running the water)
- Hold on. - What?
- I didn't pee in there. - Really?
- He just needed a place to run to. - He was trying to escape.
- I thought... - Only heartless people...
- would pee in there. - I wanted to get a grip.
I washed my face with cold water.
- He went in because it was awkward. - Gosh, the water...
I couldn't believe what I was hearing.
"Was he trying to be funny? To make her feel better?"
But I didn't think that was his intention...
because he was even more flustered by Na Rae's reaction.
That was another case of Kian84, not thinking more carefully.
If this were any other case, I would've scolded him.
But Kian84 said something ridiculous only he could say.
I was actually grateful because she laughed.
Right. It lightened the mood.
It was funny.
We needed to change the mood.
Kian84 talked about selling it online.
I really wanted to kill him.
(Joking)
He's a complete nutjob.
But what he said made me laugh.
Yes. I kept crying after arriving at the house.
But after hearing that...
Nothing made me laugh like that.
But I actually laughed out loud.
Thank you for saying so.
Gosh, no. I should thank you.
Yes. Because of what he said, you guys can now...
get to work.
Thanks to what he said, my mood went up a lot.
- Yes. Someone must be brave... - Right.
- That's all that matters. - and make a joke.
My gosh.
The waste haulers are here with their truck.
- Did you already book them? - Yes.
I made a reservation in advance.
- So... - They won't take it now, right?
No. They'll only leave the box with us for now.
They'll take the box at night.
- We can fill the box then. - Yes.
We need to weed out the yard, though.
I tried to pull out some.
I'll take care of them.
It'd be nice if you could help me...
- with whatever you can. - Okay.
- My gosh. - The truck must be here.
The truck is here.
(Surprised)
- You called a big truck. - Yes.
I had to because there's so much stuff to throw out.
Gosh, it was huge.
Come on in.
- That's the box you must fill? - Yes.
We had to put the waste in there.
I see.
- Hello. - Hello.
Do we have to remove the bench?
- That will be better. - Okay.
One, two, three.
I couldn't have gotten it done without their help.
- You can't do it alone. - Never.
How could anyone go through this alone?
(With their help, it was easy to move the bench.)
You'll bring in the truck, right?
- I'll park it here. - Okay.
When will you come back to retrieve the box?
What time should we come back?
- Around 5pm, please. - Yes.
We'll fill it up by then.
- Just like that? - Yes.
- They'll unload that? I see. - That's what they do at schools.
- Right. - We had that at my high school.
We used to throw out study guides in there.
I see. They can unload it like this.
(A massive box is unloaded to take away the unwanted items.)
I'll leave it open.
Wait. So you'll work in those outfits?
- What? - This is my outfit for today.
- Really? - I brought my work clothes.
- You did? - Why? What do you need?
- That's because... - Work pants?
- Yes. - I see. I might get scratches.
Grass might irritate your skin.
One, two, three.
(Lifting)
Gosh, look at this guy.
- He's a great worker. - He is.
- I must stay busy. - He knows what to do.
I knew it. He's a great worker. He's so helpful.
Experience is everything, I guess.
It's expected of my first servant.
I didn't have to instruct him. He stayed busy.
Gosh, he's an excellent worker.
(Whatever Na Rae asked, he always did a great job.)
(Servant84 is as loyal as anyone can be.)
- It's very close. - Okay.
- Let's go. - Let's go.
We had to buy cleaning supplies and work pants.
There's no way you could've done this alone.
There's no way.
Didn't you have a dog here?
The dog went to an animal clinic.
Really?
- My grandpa adored this dog. - Yes.
His name is Bokdol. I sent him to a clinic for now.
He's getting a health checkup too.
(Let me see.)
Where was the chilli pepper field?
Over there?
- Was it there? - No, it's here.
(Uncertain)
- The chilli pepper field was here. - It's over here.
- Na Rae's Summer School. - Yes.
There used to be so many chilli peppers here.
I think they're peanuts.
Right. We did something with peanuts...
- I don't remember the peanuts. - the last time we were here.
My gosh.
I'm glad it's slightly cloudy. It's a hot day today.
The weather forecast said it'd rain today.
We must finish before it rains then.
Luckily, it doesn't look like it's going to rain.
I think it will be a cloudy day.
- That's better for work. - Yes.
A day care was around here.
Right here. It's my kindergarten care.
Oh, yes. You used to go there too, right?
Yes.
- Hey, I can see some kids. - There are still kids here.
- You used to be one of them. - Yes.
That's my old kindergarten.
- Gosh, thank you for coming. - We need more kids.
My gosh.
First of all, let's talk about this.
Is there a hardware store nearby?
We'll see a hardware store on our way.
We'll need arm sleeves, right?
- Arm sleeves. - We need...
- Work gloves. - scrubbers.
We need to buy a pair of work pants.
Why don't we start with a meal?
- Or... - Right. We need to sort this out.
- Yes. Let's sort it out... - Hey. Yes.
- Yes. - over a meal.
(Looking around for a restaurant)
I think that's the restaurant...
- we ate at. - With your grandma?
- Yes. - Really?
Only once.
Back then, my grandma...
- wasn't in good health. - Right.
- So cooking was too much for her. - I see.
Let's go there then.
It's better to go to a place you ate at even if it's just once.
Yes. Gosh, this place looks good.
(They enter a restaurant she took her grandma to.)
This is the place. I think we ate here once.
- No? - Your grandma's place is nearby.
- Right. - You're sweating. It must be hot.
- Sit there. - Did her grandma come here often?
- Did she? - She came here often.
- Really? - Yes.
I thought that she liked cooking.
- Come on. - She cooked a feast only for me.
Of course.
She cooked so much food whenever I came over.
- She didn't want to cook sometimes. - Of course.
What brings you here?
We couldn't clean up my grandma's house.
We're here to clean it up.
They're going to help me.
(I see.)
- What's on the menu? - What should we get?
The yukhoe bibimbap is our signature dish.
Then give us three of that.
- Let's order some soup. - We should...
- order soup. - How about kimchi jjigae?
I'm craving intestine soup too.
- The intestine soup? - Try that too.
One serving of the intestine soup...
- and one serving of kimchi jjigae. - One serving of kimchi jjigae.
- Three yukhoe bibimbap, please. - Bibimbap.
- Yes. - You want to order that much food?
My gosh. This meal is like an appetizer.
- This is considered a small meal. - Right.
- We need to work today. - You must have a filling meal.
- Yes. - Gosh.
I'll give you three.
- Okay. - This looks great.
- Thank you. - Hold on. One intestine soup,
one yukhoe bibimbap...
- What was the last one? - Three yukhoe bibimbap.
- I see. Three? - Three yukhoe bibimbap.
- Three yukhoe bibimbap? - She's quite surprised.
- Kimchi jjigae and the soup too. - Kimchi jjigae too.
- Look how surprised she is. - Yes.
- All that for the three of you? - Yes.
- That's 5 servings. - She and I can eat 5 servings.
- Right. - Yes.
- We eat a lot. - The kimchi jjigae is good.
- Yes. - Yes.
What about your grandma's kimchi?
(Sighing)
Usually, people can't seem to eat it.
Should we...
(Inhaling deeply)
What are you going to say now?
- You're making me nervous. - Should I sell that online too?
I thought that you wouldn't be able to eat it.
Wouldn't it be better if we ate it for you?
What is this? Gosh, I have a headache.
Her grandma made it to be consumed.
- Right. - We can't throw that out.
- We understand your intention. - Right.
Na Rae sent me a lot of kimchi, so I ate a lot of her kimchi.
He also asked for my grandma's bone soup.
He can have a meal with the kimchi and the bone soup.
- That's perfect. Yes. - What an excellent pairing.
The 12-year-old bone soup...
- with the two-year-old kimchi. - Yes.
- That's a total of 17 years. - My gosh, that's a great meal.
He wants the kimchi.
No.
It's not that. I'm trying to think of a way to consume it.
But don't we need kimchi while having meat?
That would be a great meal and all.
- But there's a lot of kimchi. - You know what?
I'm having an identity crisis.
- I'm in the Palm Oil Family. - Okay.
- Then I should eat the kimchi. - Yes.
I'm sure it's fermented nicely.
I'm bringing it up for your sake.
You're thinking of it as a keepsake, not food.
Let's just have half of it.
- Really? - It's tasty.
- We'll eat it with your permission. - Let's eat it.
I think my grandma would want us to enjoy it.
- Of course. - Yes.
- That's what she'd want. - Yes.
- I'll serve the bibimbap first. - Thank you.
(As they think of her grandma, the yukhoe bibimbap is served.)
- My gosh. - Here's the sauce.
- The raw beef looks great. - Add it to your food.
- Okay. - The raw beef looks great.
- Gosh, it looks tasty. - Check that out.
How interesting. She added seasoned zucchini.
Gosh, this looks amazing.
There's a butchery around the restaurant.
- It's a famous butchery. - I see.
- That's right. - That's why.
- So... - The beef has a nice colour to it.
You know how it is around cattle markets, right?
- Of course. - Why does it sound familiar?
You seem very disappointed.
- Well... - I'm a good worker too.
- My gosh. - All right. Let's dig in.
- Eat a lot. - Okay.
All right. That way, I can ask you to work hard later.
(Mixing)
You get hungry after crying.
(Humming)
Our energy comes from rice.
That was some high-quality raw beef.
- It was tasty. - It was so good.
- Gosh, the raw beef is amazing. - It's tasty.
(Humming in approval)
(Enjoying his food)
Gosh, the raw beef completes the dish.
From today onward, I'll keep the house clean...
so that my family can come and use it later.
That's a good idea.
When I was born,
my grandma and grandpa built the house themselves.
- When you were born? - Yes.
There is a photo of my grandparents...
stacking up the bricks with me around.
It was taken in December of 1985.
- Your grandma... - Did your grandma build the house?
My grandma and grandpa built it.
- Just the two of them? - They built it with my dad.
- That was why I wanted to clean it. - All right.
Here is your order.
There is pepper.
(Kimchi jjigae and intestine soup will warm up their stomachs.)
- The food is really tasty. - It looks tasty.
It was to die for.
(My goodness)
- My goodness. - This is their signature dish.
Is this their signature dish?
- Yes. - A dish like this is a must here.
The butchery is nearby.
(I agree with you.)
(We can restore our strength and work now!)
This is incredible.
- Didn't you have breakfast? - What?
- Didn't you have breakfast? - This is how much I normally eat.
(Laughing)
Shall we go to the farming machine store first?
- Okay. - Okay.
The farming machine store...
will sell things like gloves and arm sleeves.
- Let's go. - All right.
Thank you for the food.
- It's on me. - What?
Food is on me today.
It was the least I could do since I wasn't paying them.
- Thank you for the food. - Thank you for the food.
Will you go to Seoul right away?
No, we'll clean the house...
- now that we've eaten. - The house.
There's someone who does maintenance work at times,
but it isn't enough since the house is unoccupied.
That's right. That happens...
when the house is unoccupied.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
- Thank you. - We'll come again.
- Shall we go? - Let's go down the street.
What should we do? Shall we buy the tools at a supermarket?
There used to be all the tools in the house.
But now, there was nothing useful.
Everything became rusty and worn.
They're sold here.
(They're sold here.)
We should get three brooms, right?
Aren't they too small?
- But... - Aren't there bigger ones?
- Let's get one of these. - Hello.
- Hello. - Hello.
We need one of these, right?
- What? - For the yard.
Please give me one gridiron pan as well.
- I'll give you one. - Okay.
Do they sell both gridiron pans and brooms?
They sell everything.
- It's a general store. - Hello.
- Hello. - We need two big ones.
- Big ones? - Yes.
That dustpan looks good.
Do you sell work pants?
Hyun Moo, pick a pair of work pants.
Hold on.
- Give me any colour. - I want pink work pants.
- I want this one. - He always buys pink items.
Yes. I'm Moorincess.
A supermarket was right next to the store.
All the places are nearby.
- They have everything. - They sell many items.
Kian84 will pick the right brand of bleach.
He's the bleach rocker.
Bleach.
- He's an expert in bleach. - Bleach rocker.
It'll be nice to have it around.
We bought so many items.
You'll use them when you organise the house.
Of course.
We had to drink coffee.
Coffee mix packets are the best.
All right.
We bought the items quickly to get back to work.
Hyun Moo, it's heavy.
It's okay. You can carry that.
- Give me that. - Here.
Right.
- I feel like I'm dying. - Thank you.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
Take care.
My goodness.
- Oh, no. I feel bad. - It's okay.
When did he open an ice cream packet?
When did he get ice cream?
Are you okay?
We bought so many liquid items.
Your back is very bent.
- I felt so bad. - You just need to walk fast.
It's raining too.
Kian84 became speechless due to exhaustion.
Are you okay?
It's too heavy, right?
- Let's hurry up and go. - Let's hurry up and go.
(He hugs the wet box.)
The bottom will tear if he doesn't hold it like that.
(Heave-ho)
For goodness' sake.
(Dropping)
We're nearly there.
Throw it.
(Groaning)
Well done.
(He becomes one with the wet box.)
- My goodness. - It must weigh over 20kg.
Well done.
- Let's hurry up and change. - Okay.
- Take a pair of work pants each. - Work pants.
- Where are the work pants? - Here.
Whose pants are these?
- Na Rae, these are yours. - Yes, give me those.
Na Rae's pants have the original colours.
The pink pants are mine.
- He likes bright colours. - The Indian pants are yours.
It'll be okay if it doesn't rain harder.
It'll be perfect. Then there won't be sunlight.
Your grandma is helping us.
- So that you wouldn't feel hot? - This weather is much better.
- This is better. - Yes. It was so hot earlier.
I'll go and change.
(Turning around)
(Taking off his pants)
Let's pluck them out.
(Moorincess' transformation)
- My goodness. - My goodness.
My goodness.
(He feels refreshed.)
Shall we cut the grass?
Okay.
(Before Na Rae comes back,)
(they clean up the yard by getting rid of the weed.)
(Pulling out)
It's hard work.
(They put their backs into the work for Na Rae who was upset.)
Both of them worked fast.
Hyun Moo.
(Na Re returns in new clothes.)
Na Rae, shall I put everything here in the box?
I think that'll be better.
- I'll load the container. - Okay.
You should clean up without hesitation.
Yes, you should throw things into the trash.
(He fills the container with items to throw away.)
Gosh.
(Meanwhile, Moomoo is still fighting against weed.)
Gosh, what are these?
This punk.
- They were growing out of cement. - This punk.
- I see. - I had a feeling that...
Na Rae and Kian84 would be better workers than me.
So, I thought about what I could do well.
Strategising.
Then I realised...
that I should begin by pulling out weeds.
Pulling out weeds won't be easy.
I became Moobicide.
- Moobicide. - I set out to dig out their roots.
I set out to make sure they never grew on this soil again.
(Here comes Super Moobicideman.)
My goodness.
Those weeds were strong.
(No matter how strong the weeds are,)
(Moobicideman will get rid of them.)
He was good.
He's like an herbicide.
I became Moobicide.
(Pulling)
It's really hard to do that.
Hyun Moo worked hard despite having no stamina.
I know.
(Weeds were covering the yard.)
Hyun Moo pulled out all the weeds.
Yes.
- The yard became bigger, right? - Yes.
Hyun Moo.
Hold on. Let me pull it out first.
Okay.
Look at that.
He's good.
(Servant84 shows his skills for the 1st time in a while.)
He worked well.
Look at him.
You're a great worker.
Has he always been good at working?
Did he become that way because of you?
Kian84 is working hard without a word.
He's really good.
- You know... - The background music is perfect.
Look at that. It's a heavy item.
(Her voice awakens his power.)
- Did he load it all by himself? - Yes.
I loaded it.
He began to talk less.
(Na Rae is in charge of the flower garden.)
My grandparents put so much work into the garden.
(She's absorbed in something without straightening her back.)
You stayed only there.
Look. The flower garden was a mess,
but there were two roses.
- Really? - Yes.
I missed them.
That was why you stayed there.
There were two red roses.
Exactly two.
(Her grandparents cherished the flower garden.)
I think my grandparents grew those roses...
from the sky.
Roses don't bloom...
without human care.
The plant is very sensitive.
When I saw the red roses,
I was determined to save them.
Roses bloom only when they receive love...
and attention.
(She looks after the roses with care.)
You can't stop...
because it weighs on your heart.
I want to save these roses because my grandma liked them.
My dad must've felt the same...
when he fixed the house.
(Sweeping)
(Servant84 sweeps the yard without a word.)
Kian84 works well.
He's good.
He's the best servant out there.
Designer servant.
"Designer servant."
(The very best Servant84 works all over the yard.)
Working with him made me realise...
- that he was really good. - Yes.
(Shouting)
Are you okay, Hyun Moo?
What are you doing?
(Moobicideman begins to act strangely.)
I was reminded of something.
In documentaries, snakes...
strangle their prey to death.
The weeds were strangling the camellia tree and rose shrub.
I became very angry.
I thought, "Today,"
"I'll take you guys on."
(Super Moobicideman is back.)
- My goodness. - The shovel is bent.
You destroyed the shovel.
- What are you doing? - What are you doing?
I became obsessed with the roots.
I set out to finish off the roots.
You definitely finished off the shovel.
(I don't know about the roots.)
(Special talent: Finishing off the shovel)
What is he doing?
(I need something other than a shovel.)
(He changes his weapon.)
(The destroyer of farming tools, Super Moobicideman)
(The third weapon)
Where are these Gollum sounds coming from?
(Gollum Moobicideman with bloodshot eyes)
(My precious!)
What are you doing?
I found the root of the weeds.
- This is the root. - Hold on.
(Sniffing)
I think it's the camellia tree.
I'm sorry.
He destroyed the roots of the camellia tree.
Did he collect a piece of the camellia tree root?
- No, he destroyed the roots. - No, I destroyed the roots.
He destroyed them.
Come on out.
I can't believe you.
Why did you attack the camellia tree?
It was growing well.
I had no energy left in my body.
The sky looks yellow.
(Laughing)
It's okay. You did well.
I won't live in a detached house.
- Did this experience help? - Yes.
I'll block all the calls from Gimpo and such.
- This won't do. - I lost all interest in a house.
(Moobicideman continues to hunt down the weeds.)
It's raining harder.
We got Goryeo celadon as well.
Don't throw it away.
It has been here ever since I was little.
You shouldn't throw away such items.
Na Rae, this is precious.
What?
It's a washboard that's made of rock.
- That's... - You should keep it.
Yes. It has been here ever since I was little.
No matter how much we throw away, this spot doesn't become clean.
- Go up there. - Let's put it up there.
Let's put it up there and push.
We worked so hard.
That was 4t.
The yard became bigger.
We've done a lot.
I can see the way now.
It's much better.
It stings. This part stings.
Are you okay?
I think I got a grass rash.
I told you that you could get grass rashes.
You got rashes, right? Don't scratch them.
- For goodness' sake. - He made them worse...
by scratching them with his gloved hands.
- Be careful not to get them. - I got grass rashes.
Why did you spread them further?
Grass irritates the skin.
It really does.
(Servant84 ignores the grass rashes and works hard.)
(To be continued)
My goodness.
- That startled me. - What?
What?
(What happened to Servant84?)
Are you serious?
My goodness.
That startled me.
- What? - What?
A praying mantis got on my neck!
- Oh, my. - My goodness.
Did it bite you?
My goodness.
I was there with you guys.
I thought it was your pet.
It's very ferocious.
It was my pet praying mantis.
- It looks cute on the screen. - That's right.
It must like me.
It's very aggressive.
- Where is it? Did it bite you? - I swatted it.
Gosh, the praying mantis startled me.
Are you hurt?
You hit it with all your might.
- It was fine. - It must be startled.
(Careful)
Here.
I let it go because I felt bad.
(Thank you.)
(They continue cleaning in the rain.)
Guys, let's have a cup of coffee.
That sounds nice.
Make it like you did in the past, okay?
I'll add three packets each.
- Three packets. - Okay. Our blood sugar is low.
- Yes. - Ice melted a lot.
It melted a lot.
- It had to be 3 packets. - It had to be 3 packets.
- Per cup? - That's right.
Why? Is it the way to go?
Simply put, we're drinking incredibly sweet coffee.
(They have a sweet beverage after hard work.)
- It's an iced vanilla latte. - An iced vanilla latte.
- It's an iced vanilla latte. - Hey.
This coffee looks terrible.
I couldn't make it any better.
Okay.
- That's... - Is it a mould?
- A mould? - It looks like a mould.
The crunchy particles make it tasty.
Jang Woo finds everything tasty.
- It's the Oath of the Peach Garden. - The Oath of the Peach Garden.
- It's tasty. - Yes.
- I'm a top-notch barista. - It stings.
My knees sting too.
- Is it a grass rash? - It's a grass rash.
- It's a grass rash. - Grass rashes are scary.
- Seriously. - I got so many rashes.
It would've been worse without the arm sleeves.
It felt prickly and ticklish because of the grass rashes.
- They got past the clothes. - That's right.
My skills have improved a lot in the past seven years.
I'm drinking a coffee mix on the bench after eight years.
When your hair is wet, it looks like you're balding.
You don't have a lot of hair.
- Really? - Yes.
- It's okay. - Hyun Moo.
Come on. It isn't that bad.
- That's right. - I take care of my hair.
- You look bad. - What's up with your hair?
Oh, no.
(I feel bad for Hyun Moo.)
This is the worst.
My goodness.
Gosh, it's getting twisted.
It only stopped raining when we were done.
Hyun Moo, shall I spray water on you?
Wash your face.
- I felt really icky. - Wash your face.
Grass was all over our bodies.
He needed to rinse his body because of the grass rashes.
All right.
What?
It's very cold, right?
He doesn't like the back wash, but he gets it done the most often.
Thank you for your hard work.
(Gosh, it's cold.)
Didn't you do it 20 times on I Live Alone?
- He loves the back wash. - I know. He does it all the time.
He has gotten more back washes from me than my dad.
Hold on.
It's cold!
My goodness.
Shouldn't we use the storehouse?
For goodness' sake!
(He squeezes his eyes shut...)
(and does Fathermoo a favour.)
He squeezed his eyes shut.
For goodness' sake!
I'll make more foam.
If I do this, I'll get more foam.
What?
(Glancing over)
Doesn't his body look strange?
It looks like the collapsed clay.
His body has an expression.
It's always crying.
I speak my mind with my chest.
That's right.
Here I go.
Look at my shoulders. My shoulders look cool.
It feels nice.
(She feels refreshed too.)
- What are we doing? - Oh, yes.
- It's so refreshing. - It's so refreshing.
How is it? How...
- Come on. - The face.
Hyun Moo's chest hair...
had become thinner than before.
I see it regularly at least once a year, so...
- I had thick hair back then. - That's right.
Such things make me realise...
(Time is passing.)
"Time passes quickly."
"I've aged a lot."
Look at that. There's less foam.
- There's less foam. - Much less.
- My chest should've turned white. - It's like a clock of life.
A clock of life?
Why is my body a clock of life to you?
- A maesaengi clock. - Maesaengi's time passes.
(Maesaengi's spring days pass.)
I've watched the rise and fall of Hyun Moo's chest hair.
- What a ridiculous thing to say. - It wasn't what I wanted, but...
(The passing time makes him stagger.)
Oh, my.
Oh, darn.
- "Oh, darn?" - Oh, darn.
Why would you say that to a person's body?
It's diabolical.
Get it trimmed.
- Get a Brazilian wax. - What?
- I bet there are many germs. - There are no germs.
(For goodness' sake)
Eight years ago, we weren't so close to each other.
We washed up separately.
There's hair on your nipples.
(Despite the passage of time)
- It's refreshing. - It's so refreshing.
What is my grandma doing? For goodness' sake.
(You and I...)
(will always be "us.")
Let's get back to work after a short break.
(Let's get back to work after a short break.)
(I Live Alone)
Kai, welcome.
- Welcome. - Hello.
- You're here even though Hue isn't. - Seriously.
- Will someone come? - There's no one to suck up to.
(He wanted to leave a good impression on Hue Park.)
(Showering him with compliments)
(Kai, you're being a suck-up today.)
How could you call him a suck-up?
(The suck-up genius even sang a serenade.)
Did you do anything with Hue the last time you two came?
We got each other's number.
- He achieved his goal. - Right.
- That was a big achievement. - A big achievement.
- Treat us to a meal! - Gosh.
Mr. Suck-Up.
- Mr. Suck-Up. - Mr. Suck-Up.
Mr. Suck-Up of the musical world.
(Mr. Suck-Up)
(There Is No End in Learning)
(Slicing)
(Kai is prepping paprikas.)
Why can't I eat like that?
(Eating a piece)
The house still looks so pretty.
It looks so trendy.
After appearing in the show,
many people told me...
that I did a great job decorating my house.
It felt great...
as it had been a while since I received a lot of attention.
- He has such a nice voice. - Right.
(Along with the sweet sound of the knife instead of his voice,)
(he prepares breakfast in a flash.)
(He heads somewhere right after getting his breakfast prepared.)
(Opening the front door)
(He can't miss out on the morning newspaper.)
(The newspaper...)
(and breakfast are set up.)
(A drink full of vitamins is prepared as well.)
As expected.
(A healthy meal is prepared like always.)
Gosh.
(Shall I read the papers?)
(Kai follows his morning routine consistently.)
He's so consistent.
You're quite similar...
- to Hue. - Right.
(Print addicts, Kai and Hue)
You were being wary of him, right?
It was for show.
It's to make an appeal to Hue.
(Unlike the suspicions, he reads naturally.)
(Looking intently)
(Grabbing)
(Underlining without hesitation)
- What is he underlining? - He's reading the papers.
(This is how he remembers articles.)
(He inputs it in his heart.)
(Let's remember "reservation-only exhibit")
Why did you circle "reservation-only exhibit?"
There were many times when I went and just came back.
- Really? - Yes.
(I won't miss it this time.)
(Taping it to the wall preciously)
Doing that keeps that in your mind for a long time.
- Right. - Right?
(He made a clipping of an exhibition the other time.)
I went there myself after paying 20 dollars.
- You actually went? - Yes.
(I'll go here soon as well.)
Tenor!
His cat?
Time to eat!
(Calling with the sound of the bowls)
Tenor!
(It's time to eat?)
You came out?
It's time to eat.
(Tenor came out right away after being called.)
You're spot on when I call you out for food.
Of course.
- Right. - That little punk.
(He quickly prepares Tenor's food.)
Enjoy your food.
(Watching with a smile)
Are you full?
I'm quite certain about this.
- Yes? - Pets take after their owners.
- Right. - Right.
Ki Bum's dogs are just like Ki Bum.
The two share Ki Bum's good points and bad points.
I can't really deny it.
It's the same with Ae Ong.
Ae Ong would never come out.
- It's a timid cat? - Ae Ong is always cautious.
Ae Ong is very introverted.
(Tenor that takes after Kai quietly heads over to get brushed.)
Let's get you brushed.
Tenor is so calm.
That feels good, doesn't it?
- Gosh, look at that! - Gosh.
That's fascinating.
Tenor gets brushed well.
That feels good, doesn't it?
Where is Tenor going?
Tenor looks just like a jaguar.
(What are you doing, Tenor?)
(Full of cuteness)
Tenor is so cute!
Let's get you brushed.
(Brushing)
That feels good, doesn't it?
I'm done.
How adorable!
(Gosh, you're so cute.)
(Kissing out of love)
That's enough for today.
(He goes to his study.)
(All-black bedroom)
Deep-green.
(He turns on his laptop in the white-tone study.)
(He gets focused instantly.)
(Typing)
- Hunt-and-peck typing. - Hunt-and-peck typing.
- Yes? - I wanted to let you know.
Of course.
Okay. Thank you.
Does he have another job?
(Getting up)
(He hurriedly packs his bag after ending the call.)
(I've packed everything.)
- Gosh. - He's wearing suspenders.
- He's wearing suspenders. - It looks like a stage costume.
They say, "Fine feathers make fine birds."
It's my combat suit.
(He dresses differently from his comfortable outfits.)
Right.
It looks really good on him.
(Picking up)
(His empty wrist is filled with his watch.)
(He even puts on his jacket.)
It fits nicely on him because he eats fruits.
Fruits?
It won't fit nicely for gukbap eaters.
- Of course not. - You're talking about me.
He looks like a profiler.
(He brings up his style with sunglasses.)
I'll be back, Tenor!
Doesn't he look like a salesman?
- A salesman? - Right.
You must be heading out to meet Hue!
That makes sense!
(Mr. Suck-Up heads out with his car.)
(Singing passionately all of a sudden)
(Waving his hands to the lingering notes)
(A special performance to celebrate the red light)
(Immersed)
- He must be going to an audition. - For a musical?
But he wouldn't be dressed like that for an audition.
- The role must be a businessman. - Could that be it?
(The car quickly moves out of Seoul.)
Where is he going?
(He heads to some place.)
It's a school.
It really is a school!
- It's a university. - Right.
(The campus is full of greens.)
It must be great to be a university student.
(Romance and youth blossom at this place.)
(He arrives at a university full of bright energy.)
Why is he at a university?
Are you going to a retreat?
With the students?
That's the worst thing to do.
Sounds great, doesn't it?
There we go.
(He naturally walks into a building.)
- Why did he come here? - I wonder.
- To take a class? - As an old student?
Is he an old student?
- What? - What is this place?
Is it a room for meetings?
He has become a student again?
Could that be it?
What's going on?
Hansei University is a school...
located in Gunpo, Gyeonggi Province.
I'm a performing arts professor,
so I am Professor Jung Ki Yeol.
- That's another name of mine. - Your name is Jung Ki Yeol?
- Your name was Ki Yeol? - Yes.
I didn't know that.
I thought his last name was Ka.
I thought that as well.
You were a full-time professor?
His name was Ki Yeol.
He was a professor too.
- He must be really busy. - If he's a full-time professor...
Yes. It has been two years...
since I have been a full-time professor.
I was a visiting professor for around three years before that.
- So five years in total. - Yes.
- I majored in vocal music. - Right.
When I was a student,
I didn't expect musicals to become this popular in Korea.
- I see. - Right.
There was no one around me...
to teach me about what to study and work on...
to become a musical actor.
Right.
So as I studied to become a musical actor,
I wanted to become someone who could teach students...
with the same struggles that I went through.
I always had that in mind,
and I was given a good opportunity...
to teach at my school.
Doesn't it take a lot of your time to be a full-time professor?
Right.
The professors of the same department...
know that I have a lot of performances.
They help me out a lot...
- and cover for me often as well. - They help you out.
They really must have wanted you to be a professor at their school.
It wasn't set up based on a specific interior design.
I set the place up like that as I didn't want the school...
to feel soulless.
- This is Kai's Room. - It's really big.
- Did you decorate it on your own? - Yes.
Really?
It has such a nice atmosphere. Check that out.
There's a piano as well.
It's not a regular professor's office.
I've never seen an office set up like that.
I thought it was a meeting room.
(Kai's traces are left around the room.)
- It's... - What is that?
- Gosh! - That's intense.
It's a photoshoot for a magazine that I feel proud of.
I placed it on one side as a piece of my memory.
It wasn't out of self-attachment.
Am I not allowed to love myself a bit?
- We didn't say anything! - Right.
When was that?
How is there a professor like that?
I performed for "Ben-Hur..."
- around that time. - "Ben-Hur."
I started working out for the first time back then.
People who are in movies or dramas are done...
after filming for that specific scene.
- Right. - But musical actors...
- They have to stay fit. - have to go through...
two months of practice and three months of performances.
Carbohydrate levels must be controlled...
for at least half a year.
It's hard to maintain a fit body.
- It's maintained for a while. - Right.
It has to be maintained for that whole period.
- That must be really tough. - Right.
(He naturally turns on the power of different items.)
(He even sets up the piano.)
(He reaches out to get everything prepared.)
It doesn't feel like a professor's office.
It feels like a bar.
(His work preparations are over.)
He looks impressive...
- He looks great. - as a professor.
(He heads somewhere right after getting to work.)
(He walks while putting on a professor's smile.)
- Hello. - Hello.
Hello.
Then...
(The school cafeteria that has meals ranging from 3 to 6 dollars.)
I'll go with pork cutlet.
(He chooses the pork cutlet right away.)
I love having meals in trays.
Same here.
- I have those trays at home. - They bring out a special vibe.
- Right. - Right.
The food that gets served at school tastes really good.
But I have a small complaint.
The food for the teaching staff...
keeps getting served based on the taste of elders.
Seaweed soup.
That looks good.
The food for the teaching staff suits my taste.
But for the students...
The students are served tastier dishes.
- Pork cutlet. - Pork cutlet.
Dishes like udon get served often.
Also... Am I allowed to say this?
When I go to the cafeteria for the teaching staff,
there are so many older professors who are eating.
So I have to greet all of them.
- "Professor Jung Ki Yeol!" - "Oh, hello, sir."
- "Professor Jung!" - "Hello."
- "I enjoyed your performance." - "Gosh, thank you."
"Are you performing these days?"
"Professor Jung!"
But when you go to the students' cafeteria,
the students will think that way about you.
- They will think that way. - Right.
"Why does that professor..."
- That was a great point. - "keep coming here?"
- "It's hard to eat." - You'll be called tactless.
- "What is that professor doing?" - I just realised that.
- Right. - The students might think that.
I see.
Pork cutlet is one of my favourite foods.
That was why I chose to have pork cutlet.
Many people have the wrong idea about me.
- "He's so strict with his food." - Right.
People think I only eat things that don't taste good.
That's terrible.
I just have a light breakfast.
I love things like gukbap.
I love naengmyeon as well.
You didn't have a body of a gukbap lover.
I love sundae gukbap.
(He walks with light steps at the thought of having pork cutlet.)
Hello.
(Peeking)
The students are pretending they haven't seen him.
- They must feel uncomfortable. - Right.
So I was making them feel uncomfortable.
Gosh!
(Don't avoid me.)
(Impressed)
(He gets a generous amount of rice.)
Thank you.
Please give me a lot of soup, ma'am.
(Smiling)
- Would you like more lettuce? - Yes, please!
Please give me a lot.
Thank you.
(Filling up the plate)
- She gave him so much. - That's quite a lot.
Thank you.
- Enjoy your meal. - Thank you.
He speaks in a pleasant manner.
Hi.
"Let's get up quickly."
(Joking)
They would mouth the words.
I had no idea they would feel that way.
- "Smile." - "Gosh, it feels so uncomfortable."
"Smile."
(Slicing)
Gosh, that looks good. It's making me want some.
Gosh, it's crispy.
That's a great privilege.
- Right. Along with that soup. - It's half-transparent.
Gosh, that looks good!
(Taking a big bite)
(This is indeed my favourite food.)
I can't help it. I'm having pork cutlet later.
It feels very nice to see university students.
Right. There's a young energy that can be felt from them.
There's a certain energy that can be felt from school cafeterias.
- Right. - After eating at the cafeteria,
it's the best feeling to skip class.
It's the best feeling...
- to skip class. - Right.
Having some beer between classes...
- and deciding to skip class. - Gosh.
That's the best feeling.
You get put on academic probation right after that.
You then beg the professor for forgiveness in tears via email.
- The email of tears. - The email of tears.
"Professor!"
- When the weather is nice, - "Just this once!"
you really don't want to be in class.
(He also takes a bite of the fresh salad.)
That must be good.
(He takes a sip of the soft cream soup as well.)
(This is it.)
It's the Solitary Gourmet.
(Even when he ate sushi in Jeju...)
It seems like he really loves food.
He enjoys his food.
Right. He savours the taste.
(This is the cafeteria pork cutlet.)
(Sighing)
He's eating cafeteria pork cutlet...
and making it seem like a photoshoot!
This is what the students will say behind him.
"There he goes again."
"Why is he sitting there?"
(Laughing)
I want cafeteria food.
I really want cafeteria food too.
- It's of good quality. - The food is great.
You never feel full with cafeteria food.
(Smiling)
(Can you feel it?)
(Can you feel this fantastic taste?)
(The fireworks of flavour mesmerize his tongue.)
Is this the right song to be playing at this moment?
Is there a need for this while eating cafeteria food?
(It's good, isn't it?)
Who is he doing that to?
Isn't he just doing that on his own?
It's creepy. There's no one there!
What's going on?
People who don't have friends do that.
They would act like they're greeting others.
They would put their jackets on the other side.
And the students sitting at a different table would go,
"There he goes again."
- "Look over there." - "There he goes again."
(He finishes his meal in a flash.)
(The last bite)
(He pleasantly finishes his 5-dollar meal.)
Isn't that great for five dollars?
- That's a great meal. - Of course.
- Definitely. - If you consider...
the prices these days...
A few pieces of Pikachu pork cutlet would cost five dollars.
No. One piece costs three dollars.
- They're expensive these days. - What?
- Three dollars for a small piece. - You Pikachu as well?
(He cleans up neatly as well.)
(I should get back soon.)
(Professor Kai heads to the cafe after eating.)
Here you are.
(Rummaging)
- Here it is. - Is it a coupon?
These...
are my students' cards.
- What is going on? - Right.
Are you getting their stamp cards stamped for them?
You get it stamped for them?
Each time he buys coffee.
That's sweet of you.
Have you ever thought about using one of their stamp cards?
(No way!)
Thank you.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
The stamp cards are left there?
Yes. Their names are written there.
They get their own stamp cards stamped.
(After getting the stamps...)
Right. He got four cups of coffee.
(Greeting pleasantly)
Hello, Professor.
It's a different professor.
(Walking quickly)
He walks quickly.
- I'll see you later. - Gosh.
He wants good grades from him.
There's nothing he's positive about.
He's getting meaner and meaner.
(Joking)
(Has he returned to Kai's Room?)
Hello.
- Who are they? - According to your tastes.
Thank you.
- This one is sweet. - Because they're your seniors?
Yes. It was the day of a professor's meeting.
There are four full-time professors.
We have a full-time faculty meeting once or twice a week.
We have a group chat too.
There isn't a specific meeting room, so we normally gather...
in the department head's room. That's what we normally do,
but my room became like a gathering lounge.
- There are many times... - Because it's well-decorated.
where the meeting is held in my room naturally.
They're a lot older than me,
and they're more experienced.
I'm the absolute youngest.
I'm so loved by the professors.
They don't ask me to get anything,
- but I do to be on their good side. - He's Mr. Suck-Up.
- Yes, Mr. Suck-Up. - You ought to be one.
- He sure is Mr. Suck-Up. - Mr. Suck-Up?
I get drinks according to their tastes.
A hot Americano for the department head,
a vanilla latte for Professor Oh,
yuzu ade for Professor Lee Dong Geun,
- and an iced Americano for me. - Iced Americano?
This clip itself is a video letter...
- for Hue Park. - Tell me about it.
- It's a self-introduction video. - It's a profile.
"Take a look at my video profile."
His everyday life is filled with flattery.
It's not that there's a target for his flattery today.
We're seeing the everyday life...
- of a flatterer. - Exactly. The life of a flatterer.
- The life of a flatterer. - The life of a flatterer.
- How to survive with flattery. - Jabbering.
I've never seen someone with an image of a flatterer.
- It's cute. - It's really cute.
- I like it. - It'll go crazy on Christmas.
Jung Flatterer.
Let's quickly go through the full-time faculty meeting...
- since everyone has a class. - All right.
We're preparing an event for the 20th anniversary...
- of our department. - That's a big event.
Professor Kai,
- give us your opinion. - All right.
How about you host the event, Professor Kai?
- Please host the event. - All right.
- Okay. - Also, how about...
- a narration? - Sounds good.
- Please check on it. Music too. - All right.
I thought it'd be nice to have such elements.
We need to decide on the title of the show.
Let's focus on the future instead of the past.
He looks like a little kid among the professors.
- He looks like a new recruit. - Yes.
- He also feels like Eui Chan. - Yes.
He looks like a smart boy.
(Professor Kai looks smart for some reason.)
What do you think, Professor Kai?
- Yes. - That's scary.
- What do you think, Professor Kai? - What do you think, Professor Jung?
I think it sounds good.
- I think it sounds good. - He thinks everything is good.
(He finds him cute.)
They don't look like scary seniors.
Or Professor Kai could say something in the middle.
How about you being in charge...
- of comments? - Okay, I got it.
A narration or any comments for promotion.
(Onstage, he's full of charisma.)
Yes, he's really amazing.
He's the king of the musical scene.
Of course.
I thought it'd be nice to have such elements.
I think it'd be nice for the students if you dropped by.
- Please be in charge. - All right.
- For the graduate school... - Yes.
We'll leave most of it to Professor Kai.
- That's... - Because he keeps saying yes to it.
- All right. - They're making you do everything.
- All right. - Okay.
Do you ever say no?
- It'll be too hard. - "I don't think I can do it."
Well, they give me tasks...
- that I can manage, to begin with. - Goodness.
- That's a great mindset. - Yes.
You tend to take good care of a junior like him.
- Of course. - You'd take good care.
That must be why he's loved.
You've done many concerts,
so I think you're someone...
who can see the overall picture best among us.
Shall I get congratulatory videos from actors?
- He's making unnecessary work. - That'd be great.
He's the type to make more work.
- Can we include that? - That'd be lovely.
- All right. - That'd be great.
If you take a look at it,
- you'll have a clearer picture. - Yes.
It looks like Professor Lee...
- took detailed care of it. - My goodness.
- Thank you. - Sure.
That was the most touching comment.
- We're wrapping up amicably. - Yes.
- Let's finish up the meeting. - All right.
- Great work, everyone. - Thank you.
- Great work. - All right.
(I did well today, as usual.)
I'm off for lunch.
(Bowing)
- I'll get going. - Okay.
(He keeps bowing.)
- Please take good care of it. - He's doing well socially.
- All right. - Thank you.
- I should learn from him. - It's difficult.
He's watching them from the back too.
He's bowing to their shadows too.
(Polite Mr. Suck-Up returns to his room.)
(Taking out his laptop)
(To be continued)
(He's busy even after the meeting.)
(Squeaking)
Hello, Professor.
Oh, Seung Yoon, come on in.
- Who is it? - Is he a TA?
Is he a TA?
(He sits naturally in front of Professor Kai.)
Come on in.
Hello.
- Hello. - Hi. Welcome.
- I'm sorry, Professor. - Hi, come on in.
- His students? - Hi.
- Hello, ma'am. - Hello.
- Hello. - Hello.
A teacher?
She's the pianist.
(The accompanist sits in front of the piano.)
It's the class I spend the most time on at school.
It's a major practical class.
I teach them 1-on-1,
or I teach them in a group, like an open lecture.
I teach their singing in depth.
Today's the day I teach a major lecture.
- Oh, it's a class. - That's where you have class.
- Yes. - You have class there?
- Yes. - Isn't there a practice room?
There is, but my office...
- helps them focus better. - That must be more fun.
The students must be so happy to get a direct lesson from him.
Is it possible to get a private lesson...
from someone at the top of the industry?
- It's a really precious time. - Gosh, Professor Kai...
Shall we begin with you, Seung Yoon?
Yes, sir.
- Why don't you sing here today? - Okay.
Which year are they in?
They're seniors who are about to graduate.
- You'll get to see them onstage. - That's right.
(Nervous)
(She starts playing the piano.)
(Let's give it a listen.)
("Since I'm Alive" from the musical, "Ben-Hur")
Gosh, he has a nice voice.
(As soon as the lesson starts, Mr. Suck-Up disappears.)
(The look in Professor Kai's eyes has changed.)
(Soon, the song reaches its climax.)
(He's become serious for some reason.)
(Thinking)
(Even if it's just for once)
- That's not good. - Okay.
(He points out the part the student needs to fix.)
You should keep singing that part in the same tone.
You suddenly lose breath if you sing like that.
Then you can't hit the high notes that come after.
- You only need to fix that. - Okay.
- Okay? - Yes.
- Great. Seong Beom, you're next. - Okay.
(He wraps up with a compliment. The next student sings.)
("The Hymn of Death")
I knew it.
- He has great vocal projection. - It's nice.
(But Professor Kai seems serious.)
(The end of life)
All right.
You have a great voice.
- Goodness. - He's like ZO ZAZZ...
of the musical scene.
- He has that vibe. - ZO ZAZZ?
He does have that vibe.
But...
"But?" That's scary.
I wonder if your voice could go on a diet.
A diet of his voice?
You can go on a diet with your voice?
Are you saying I shouldn't go overboard?
It's good that your emotional energy is added to it,
but you can use less of that energy.
Okay.
You can go on a diet with your voice?
If you try to use a full-bodied sound,
you use extra strength.
- It becomes too much. - It's really difficult...
to maintain your voice in a pleasant tone.
Especially in musicals,
you sing about 20 songs...
- for three hours. - That's right.
So if you fail to control your vocal cords from the start,
it can become difficult.
It's not like you perform...
- for three hours only on that day. - That's not the case.
- You perform the next day too. - You're right.
He can give that kind of feedback...
- because he's still active. - He can give that.
You must've figured out the pros and cons of each student.
I totally have them figured out.
If your voice could go on a diet a little, you can hit...
- I mean your voice. - Yes.
- If your voice could go on a diet, - It's a little...
you can reach a tone 2 or 3 notes higher.
I see. Okay.
(Let me show you how it's sung.)
- It's not this. The waves - Okay.
- It needs to ripple more lightly. - Oh, a diet like that.
Don't show your strength like that at once.
Keep it first...
(Should I take it out or not?)
- You get what I mean, right? - Yes.
You know swordsmen, right? With a sword like this.
If you take the sword out, you can get rid of them at once,
but you hold it.
- Goodness. - Okay.
What does it mean? I don't get it.
- So you have to tease. - Exactly.
- He's indeed good. - Like a see-through.
He's indeed good.
"See-through?" What do you mean?
Don't take off everything.
It's like an audition show.
I understood.
- You can totally do it. - Okay.
(Professor Kai wraps up with a compliment and encouragement.)
Now, shall we have Dong Hyeon sing?
Okay.
Let's go!
He brought a nice song.
A nice song?
(What does he mean by a nice song?)
- A nice song. - Here you go.
"Love is Cruel."
(The score he got is none other than...)
"Beethoven?"
It's the number you sang, Kai.
(It's the number Kai sang in the musical, "Beethoven.")
(Feeling a surge of emotion)
But it's Park Hyo Shin's version.
Oh, no.
Well, the score...
He must've listened to that version more.
Still!
He should've used correction tape...
and written, "Kai's version."
- Goodness. - I lacked tact.
You lacked a lot.
(Embarrassed)
("Beethoven")
(He lets go of the embarrassment and starts singing.)
(He becomes serious when they start singing.)
(Singing)
No, that's not right.
- It was good until this part. - Okay.
Don't go like this.
(Singing)
(The sound projects clearly and powerfully.)
(Mesmerized)
Like how you use a claw machine,
- you need to snatch right away. - Okay.
You can't go like this.
(Sing like how you use a claw machine.)
Like this.
- But if you don't do that, - Okay.
then you'll lose directions.
There are many times when you don't understand...
professors' directions.
Yes, there are many times when they say difficult things.
- You know a burger, right? - Yes.
You ordered a burger,
- and there's cheese, lettuce... - That's what I mean by difficult.
It drives me crazy.
What burger? What is it?
(Tell me quickly.)
- Since there's a sauce inside, - Yes?
you have to press it hard.
Imagine that you're taking a small bite.
(What do you mean, Professor?)
(Sing like you're pressing a burger.)
(Confused)
But how's your version?
- Maybe you just wanted a burger. - I know.
- I don't understand what he means. - What is he saying?
Imagine a gently rippling creek.
Let's say there's moss floating.
- Yes. - You use a sieve...
to remove it.
You can't scoop up the mud on the bottom of the creek.
- Okay. I got it. - Don't sing like this.
Go like this. That way, you can sing more easily.
- My love - Gosh.
You have to keep fighting...
like you're catching a whale with a fishing rod.
Make it taut.
Catching a whale with a fishing rod?
This is what I meant by catching a whale.
When you hit high notes,
don't use your strength.
You need to sing like you're snatching the notes.
That's what I wanted to say, so I used that expression.
Talking about it now makes me realise that the students...
must've not understood clearly.
Of course, my comparison...
is a little fairytale-like.
But that's what singing is like.
No other theories...
- can describe it. - That's right. It's hard.
This is what I always tell my students.
You should be able to paint with your voice.
If you want to sing well, you need to have a rich imagination.
Your voice...
We often think...
that our throats burst or that our voices burst out.
As you hit high notes,
you have a tendency to make your voice burst out.
But if you think about it technically,
the sound closes up as you hit high notes.
It needs to go through a narrow path.
Could you give us an example?
I think I get him.
You do?
(You get it?)
I may not be able to sing, but I get what he means.
Then get a one-point lesson from him.
Actually, he's the most eager to sing well.
- He's the most eager. - That's right.
- Why are you so eager? - I'm eager too.
What? Singing?
(Once he starts singing,)
(he sings his heart out until everyone gets sick of it.)
(Music84 loves singing to the point it brings tears to his eyes.)
Music is for everyone.
Among the songs with high notes...
He can sing pop song too, right?
Shall I try singing high notes with a closed throat?
- Yes. - I'll sing with my throat closed.
- Sing while closing it. - You're singing while closing it?
Gosh, I'm embarrassed all of a sudden.
Here we go.
(Warming up)
(Shaking his head)
(You're my everything)
(You're my destiny)
(I can't break up with you)
(The higher the notes get,)
(the more mournful it gets.)
He closed it well.
(Somewhere farther away from forever)
(Tell me you're happy)
(Heaven)
He closed it.
You're applauding?
- It's because... - His singing contains life.
- That's right. - Of course.
I think it's a hard life.
I took vocal lessons before too.
- A vocal lesson? - I wanted to hit high notes.
Actually, hitting high notes...
No, you can totally hit them.
- Even he can? - Of course.
- Really? - Yes, you just...
Easily put, the start of your voice.
Imagine the vocal cords aren't here...
but over here.
- A head voice. - Yes, just imagine it.
Imagine that it's here.
It doesn't go like this.
The sound comes from here.
That's it.
(I'll give it a try too.)
(Singing)
(Desperately bringing up his vocal cords)
Maybe he brought up the voice in the wrong way.
(Please stop.)
I think it's much better than before.
What is?
- It's because... - You're forcing it.
What was that?
I think that was pretty good.
I explained it to you briefly earlier.
- You're all seniors. - Yes.
You should be...
starting your careers now.
- Yes. - Then...
you need to choose good works...
that fit your characters and voices.
I think that's the most important part.
You should consider that too.
All right.
Okay, that's all for today.
- Thank you. - Goodness.
- Thank you. - "That's all for today."
Thank you.
(Thank you, Professor.)
- I want to learn from him too. - Thank you.
Prepare for the next class well.
- All right. - Got it.
Let's discuss that a lot.
- All right. - Can I choose a different song?
The more songs you have, the better.
All right.
Can I also choose a different song?
Yes, choose a different one. Which one do you want to sing?
Actually, there's a genre I prefer.
What is it?
- For example? - Something bright and fun...
- Hey. - like "Memphis."
That's good!
You should be singing a number from "Kinky Boots."
(Encouraging and supporting sincerely until the end)
I think you'll be good at it.
I'll give it a try. Thank you, Professor.
- Thank you, Professor. - Thank you, Professor.
The students have stronger faith...
when they meet a professor who's still active in the field.
They'd swarm around him to take his advice.
- Thank you, Professor. - Thank you.
(Professor Kai, the top in his field, finishes his class.)
(Kai finally leaves his room.)
(Sliding)
(Away)
(He sets off after changing his status to "away.")
Is he off work?
Oh, is it not "away" when he gets off work?
(He walks past...)
(the parking lot?)
He should have dinner now.
(Is he on his way to have a soulful dinner?)
- At the cafeteria? - Is he having it at the cafeteria?
Of course.
Goodness.
What...
- It's a theatre. - It's an auditorium.
(The students are in the middle of practice.)
(Amazed)
(The actors are completely immersed in their roles.)
So that's how they practice.
It's a small theatre located within our school.
We hold a regular performance every semester.
The students gather almost every day...
to prepare for it.
I visited their practice...
to root for them.
There's something you gain from such encounters.
That's why I can't stop appearing in audition shows.
It feels a little weird.
After the shoot, I tend to go to the studio.
- Right away. - So...
- It's really tiring, - I get what you mean.
but there are so many things you're inspired by.
Thanks to the participants?
After all the classes,
I can't leave my office easily.
You're inspired by them.
(Professor Kai came to get inspired and to root for them.)
(They exchange greetings quietly so they wouldn't interrupt.)
(Taking the empty seat)
(They finally started the musical number confidently.)
(You look so handsome and sexy)
(Getting excited as though he's at an actual concert hall)
It's of high quality.
They're good.
The students from my school...
- They're good. - Yes.
They also won the grand award...
from a college musical festival.
- I bet they did. - They're top-notch.
(The students show off their top-notch skills they honed.)
(Doing a sexy body roll)
(Impressed)
- They're good. - Yes.
(Dancing in perfect sync)
Isn't that the guy from earlier? Is he a different guy?
The one who asked a question at the end?
He is.
(Acting cute)
I think he'll be good with "Kinky Boots" numbers.
You're right. He likes lively songs.
(Proud)
Through my students,
I reflect on myself.
They'd keep me alert.
There are many things...
- I learn from them. - You learn from them instead.
(These days, he learns a lot at the same time.)
It's true that it's physically tiring,
but in terms of energy and skills,
I keep getting refilled.
- Right, you get refilled. - In that sense,
it's a school for me as well...
and a place of learning.
He must reaffirm his original intention there.
The desperation from people of that age...
- That's right. - Their passion is something...
- you can't learn elsewhere. - That's true.
- That's the only place. - Right.
That's right. The desperation.
- The passion. - The energy from the desperation.
It's my driving force.
(The energy from the students is my driving force.)
Everyone, you are...
You are really good.
- Yes! - Thank you!
- Thank you! - Thank you!
I can tell how hard you worked...
from your faces. I love it.
Here's the thing, though.
Enjoying it fully onstage...
is complete faith.
And I can see it from you guys.
I hope you'll practice happily just like this. All right?
- Yes! - Yes!
- Good luck! - Thank you!
He's indeed a great professor.
(A word of encouragement from a senior and a professor)
(He exits quietly from the students' stage.)
(Professor Kai's Playbook)
(Next story)
(A key player in the Korean band boom, DAY6)
("DAY6 Writes History, Goyang Stadium Sold Out")
(The powerful sound of drums that adds to the fun of live performance)
(The energetic youngest drummer of DAY6)
Hello.
(DAY6's Dowoon)
(It's been 5 to 6 years since he started living alone.)
(Dowoon's house in all-white)
(Filled with items that suit him as a musician)
(Current time is 2:40am.)
(He busily gets ready since early dawn.)
(It's been really long.)
(A pier?)
(How many webfoot octopuses do you want to catch?)
(A hundred.)
(With ambition, the boat sets sail.)
(My favourite hobby, sea fishing)
(Shall I show off my skills?)
(Sturdy)
Gosh, this one looks good.
(I'm getting a good feeling.)
(You're the best, captain.)
(The person he's visiting to share the webfoot octopus)
(It's Lee Sung Woo of No Brain, whom he admires.)
(Why did you catch so many?)
(You know I'm seasoned.)
(How much would this cost?).
(Come on.)
(Do you want to see Dubu sing?)
(A Truly Fun Day)
(After sending off the long-kept stuff...)
(You guys...)
(helped me take the first step.)
(The first step?)
(Are you saying there will be a second step?)
(The actual second step for the guys she's grateful to)
(Pork belly, ramyeon, and makgeolli)
(I'll grill it deliciously.)
I mean... Oh, dear.
(Put it back on. It's okay.)
(- No. - Don't throw it away.)
- You could die. - Why would you throw it away?
(I can laugh, thanks to these guys.)
(To your grandma and grandpa)
Good job.
(Exclaiming)
(Let's eat in earnest.)
(Slurping)
(It tastes amazing after working hard.)
(It brought back old memories.)
(Being with them made him feel like he was back in the old days.)
(I don't know if I can give this to you because it rained.)
- What is it? - What do you think, Na Rae?
(Turn around.)
Take a look. One, two, three.
(I can't believe it.)
(Choked up)
(He choked too before he knew it.)
(Right now, our hearts are the same.)
That's our own way.
(In the Name of Family)